Haimantika Mitra

Portfolio: haimantika.com Talks: haimantika.com/talks Github: github.com/haimantika

Summary

Haimantika Mitra is an experienced engineer with 2.5 years experience in developer relations and a degree in electronics and communication engineering. She is proficient in the following technologies:

- Languages: Python, HTML, TailwindCSS, JavaScript, SQL, Bash
- Frameworks: Astro, Hugo, Svelte, NodeJS, Django
- Tools: Docker, GIT, Azure, Microsoft Power Platform
- Other Skills: Community Management, Developer Education and Experience, Technical Documentation, and Public Speaking

EXPERIENCE

Hashnode Remote

Developer Advocate (Full-time)

January 2024 - Present

Email: haimantikamitra@gmail.com

Mobile: +918101121869

- Developer Education & Experience: Built developer documentation on Hashnode Headless CMS with various web developement frameworks that helped skill and onboard 1000+ developers as well as enterprise customers.
- Building communities and programs: Grew community by 20 % by leading community growth efforts and championing efforts for Diversity and Inclusion with initiatives such as 'Breaking Barriers' during international women's day. Reached potential customers by driving awareness work through meetups, conferences and ambassador programs.
- Building integrations: Enabled 500+ users to build with our product and AI through product integrations.
- **Developing content**: Improved viewership and engagement on content by 50 % by creating a strategy for multi modal content covering both written and video content. Collaborated on company's branding efforts that helped in onbaoarding more developers

more developers.

Appwrite

Remote

Developer Advocate (Full-time)

April 2022 - December 2023

- Building communities and programs: Grew the community by over 100 % with various initiatives such as 'OSS Fund' that led to winning the 'Most Welcoming Developer Community' award at DevRelCon London. Championed diversity and inclusion efforts by leading 'Beyond the binary' program that was aimed to empower lesser represented genders in tech. Through these programs, I helped build strong partnerships with open-source communities, increasing brand recognition and growing GitHub starts from 10,000 to 40,000+.
- Developer Education & Experience: Empowered developers by contributing to product documentation, writing technical blogs and leading educational initiatives such as GitHub Octernship and Hacktoberfest, that led to winning the 'GitHub Phenomenal Education' award.
- Building integrations: Enabled 100k+ developers build with Appwrite through various integrations. These integrations were critical in expanding the functionality of our product, resulting in increased user satisfaction and adoption.
- Developing content: Contributed to Appwrite's branding efforts by developing both written, and video content, including social media. These efforts led to doubled social media reach and helped in reaching potential customers.
 Microsoft
- Technical Support Engineer (Full-time)

April 2021 - March 2022

- Customer support: Empowered Microsoft customers troubleshoot problems related to Outlook and Exchange.
- Contributed to Microsoft Learn Documentation: Built tutorial on Microsoft Power Platform that was helpful in student developer education and Microsoft learn student ambassadors. Also helped in building technical blogs on Microsoft Azure and Power Automate

Projects

- Microsoft Teams Bot: Built a Microsoft Teams Bot using Microsoft Power Platform, that can be used by communities to answer support queries.
- GitHub Action: Built a GitHub action using Python and Docker, that automates your Machine Learning model training, with the help of autofeat python package.
- Contributing Guide Generator: Built a Contributing Guide generator applications, that uses HTML, TailwindCSS and OpenAI to help you write contributing guides for your open source projects.
- Blogging site: Built a blogging site using Appwrite and Astro.
- Query converter: Built a query converter, that converts AQL to JSON.

EDUCATION

Siliguri Institute of Technology

Siliguri, India

Bachelor of Technology - Electronics and Communication; GPA: 9.21

July 2017 - June 2021

Honors and Awards

- Winner of Smart India Hackathon October 2020
- Winner of GitHub Actions Hackathon, 2020
- Runners up of "Greatest Contribution to Society" award for OSS Fund, in DevRelCon London, 2023
- Been a speaker at multiple conferences in India and abroad since 2020.
- Featured in multiple blogs by Microsoft about my journey in tech.